[Music]
[Música]
Well nice to have you here Good
bueno encantado tenerte por aquí Buenas
evening family Good evening Thank you very much
noches familia Buenas noches Muchas
thank you
gracias gracias
yes yes yes yes
sí sí sí sí
for the
por fin
weekend over there Javier's plaque
de semana por ahí la placa de Javier
canijo
canijo
de leche
de leche
normalized let's say that everyone is very
normalizado digamos que todos son muy
good when it comes to giving an
queda bien a la hora de brindar una
opinion So I say a little more than
opinión Entonces yo digo un poco más de
3 years and I am very critical I am
3 años y como que soy muy crítico Soy
like a very honest role such good
como un papel muy honesto tal bueno
basic in person So let's say that as a
básico en persona Entonces digamos que a
result of that eruption people have become
raíz de esa erupción la gente se ha
very upset very important
molestado mucho mucho importante
Yes yes yes the second FM channel
Sí sí si el canal segunda FM
subscribers in nothing that will
suscriptores dentro de nada que va a
surpass main but for sure for sure
superardo principal pero seguro seguro
YouTube
YouTube
now in the secondary channel I make
ahora en el en el canal secundario hago
like 14 million visits while
como 14 millones de visitas mientras que
in the principality I make three
en el principado hago tres
shorts that go viral and they catch a
shorts que se viralizan y pillan una
lot they don't make money but because
barbaridad no dan dinero pero porque
YouTube
YouTube
and well there was today in secondary what
y bueno había de hoy en la secundaria lo
goes viral the most and what happens has
que más se viraliza y lo que pasa ha
literally copied you top and It works
copiado literalmente a ti top y Funciona
very well it works well but it gives you a
muy bien funciona bien pero te da una
biological exposure
exposición biológica
Maybe a million visits
A lo mejor un millón de visitas
depending a lot because it only counts you I
dependiendo mucho porque solo te cuenta
think what is seen from a PC and not from a
creo lo que se ve desde PC y no desde
mobile they can generate € 6 € 5.  millions
móvil pueden generar 6 € 5 €. millones
of lists
de listas
and I think they're even going through
y Es que creo que están pasando hasta de
your account I'm going to see when
la cuenta de ti todo voy a ver cuándo
the last tic toc was I didn't realize they
fue el último tic Toc no me he enterado
uploaded it I uploaded
que subieron lo subí yo
the high five barb It happened
lo de la puya del choca
to me too that's why I don't make the
A mí también me pasaba por eso no me la
decision also the guy offered it to me I
decisión también me lo ofrecido el chico
told him I was going to do it now because I
le he dicho que lo iba ahora porque
have a specific editor a
tengo editor específico
bunch of Rodrigo's stuff comes out that one
sale pila de cosas de Rodrigo que esa
puts a four I don't know who's talking about the
pone un cuatro no sé quién habla de la
rhyme I don't know what I'm saying
rima no sé qué digo
[Music]
[Música]
direct
directo
the anime but that's how they catalog it in some
el anime pero así catálogo de alguna
way but nothing I think there are ways and they
manera pero nada Creo que hay formas y
form what also you who are a
forman lo que además tú que eres un
world you who are from a world outside of
mundo tú que eres de un mundo fuera de
The battles that to me I am
Las batallas que a mí a mí se me
criticized a lot of the ways you know what I
recriminar mucho de las formas sabes lo
want to tell you or rather truly
que te quiero decir o sea verdaderamente
the question you think
la pregunta tú crees
that the climate
que el clima
that has been a soporific battle the
que ha sido una batalla soporífera la
most disappointing battery of the day
batería más decepcionante de la jornada
but by far or rather it hasn't been Neither
pero de lejos o sea no ha estado Ni bien
Mister bego nor has it been good it serves and it's that
Mister bego ni ha estado bien sirve y es
on top of that It has a signature not put in a single one
que encima Tiene firma no metido ni una
And it's that Mister robbery neither In the end they
Y es que Mister robo tampoco Al final se
go to the  replica because they were
van a la réplica porque es que estaban
fighting to see who did worse, I
luchando por ver quién lo hacía peor
really don't know why, chicka is
verdaderamente no sé por qué tipa está
super unfocused, she hasn't concentrated
súper descentrado no se ha concentrado
at any moment in the battle,
en ningún momento la batalla
a really bad day, a really bad day that I
un día malísimo un día malísimo que
hope doesn't happen again and that it does
espero que no se vuelva a repetir y que
n't affect her, not in the future
no no le afecte no de cara al futuro
because she had a bad day, I'm going to
porque ella ha tenido un mal día voy a
be, I don't know if she was conditioned because
ser no sé si estaba condicionada porque
you'll see colleagues and sorrows and such or she had a bad
verás colegas y penas y tal o tenía mal
day for something personal that can happen
día por algo personal que puede pasarlo
in the end they are people and they are
al final son personas y están
conditioned to feelings,
condicionadas a sentimientos a
situations, contexts And this and that
situaciones a contextos Y esto y lo otro
but the real battle has been
pero la batalla de verdad ha sido
frankly forgettable or poriferous
francamente olvidable o porífera
profession and measures be it if in the end it is
profesión y medidas sean si al final es
to improve and listen to me Buy yourself another
para mejorar y escúchame Cómprate otro
microphone what I want to tell you is that there are
micrófono lo que te quiero decir que hay
much better microphones and since you have them I can't it's not a problem What
mucho micrófono mejor y ya que tú tienes
happens is that for
no puedo no pasa nada Lo que pasa que a
me there is like a Trail, I am followed by
mí hay como una Estela a mí me persigue
many trails, many lies, many
muchas estelas muchas mentiras muchas
fallacies at the beginning people said
falacias al principio decía la gente
totally lies, of course, I mean,
totalmente mentiras claro
with me you can talk, you can
o sea conmigo se puede hablar se puede
argue about anything, I have
argumentar de cualquier cosa no tengo
no problem,
ningún problema
sectors of freestyle that I have
sectores del freestyle a los que
criticized have obviously invented
criticado evidentemente se han inventado
things like that you count for  insult them
cosas como que cuentas para insultarlos
like if there's a fascist that I'm
como que si hay un facha que yo soy
racist that I do get angry and this that that
racista que yo sí se enojo y esto que lo
then you see all my
otro luego ves a todos mis colegas de
lifelong colleagues from the neighborhood and they're all from
toda la vida del barrio y son todos de
Colombia they're all from the Dominican Republic it
Colombia son todos de República
's things
son cosas
from Instagram
de Instagram
we knew that the hot one is the one of the
sabíamos que la candente es la de las
forms and now that I'm evil
formas y ahora que soy malvado
hostilities like I [ __ ] on the [ __ ] and
hostilidades como me cago en la [__] y
the way of expressing myself while the other
la forma de expresarme mientras el otro
is threatening me but he says the gender
me está amenazando pero dice el género
when we were talking about Dallas
cuando hablábamos lo de Dallas
in a battle it's fine Now that they
en una batalla está bien Ahora que le
call him out and yours of mine we have
llamen fuera y los tuyos de mis tenemos
to interpret what is the fiction of
para interpretar lo que es la ficción de
reality and many things I'm
la realidad y muchas cosas
not saying that it's right but they are allowed
No digo que esté bien pero se permiten
in fiction I mean certain
en la ficción quiero decir ciertos
roles up
papeles arriba
when they go up on stage the judges don't
cuando suben al escenario los jueces no
give any opinion they just put
dan ninguna opinión simplemente ponen
the numbers and until the week
los números y hasta la semana
[Music] Of course of course what
[Música]
happens is that maybe it can
lo que pasa es que a lo mejor puede
generate certain reprisals when it comes to
generar ciertas represalias a la hora de
explaining a vote
explicar un voto
in the end a got talent
al final un got talento
damn It's that the last time I came to
[__] Es que la última vez que vine a
defend freestyle for by
defender al freestyle por por de manera
indirectly it's my turn to defend this
indirecta me toca defender a mí este
new because freestyle and in the end
nuevo porque freestyle y al final estaba
I was here mediating in a situation that
yo aquí mediando en una situación que a
me I was in the middle, obviously
mí Estaba en el medio que evidentemente
first of positions with the freestyle
primero de posiciones con el freestyle
but then when Mister ego comes in I
pero luego cuando entra Mister ego Yo
try to be a little in the middle and be as
trato está un poco en el medio y ser lo
objective and neutral as possible,
más objetivo y neutral posible
a friend of mine, obviously And on
un colega mío pues evidentemente Y
top of that my controversy channels are about
encima mi canales de polémica es de
gossip Well yeah maybe my
salseo Pues si a lo mejor mi canales de
fruit channels Well maybe I won't make a video
frutas Pues a lo mejor no hago un vídeo
maybe I'll put one of yours telling him how
a lo mejor pongo un tuyo diciéndole qué
ugly it is that this guy is allowed to
feo que este que se permita que este tío
say this they
diga esto
try to comment on everything that happens he
tratan de comentar todo lo que pase él
missed that Well it's normal that I
se me pasó eso Pues normal que yo
comment on the gossip and the
comente el salseo y la
controversy I go to Seville
polémicamente voy a Sevilla
in Spain
en España
me and Chulo what we do It's trying to
yo y el Chulo que hacemos Es intentar
do it in a different way that maybe it
hacerlo de otra forma que a lo mejor no
wasn't the same we taught before that there are
era la misma clasemos antes que hay
people who are doing it like that well
gente que lo estoy haciendo así bueno
each one but I am trying as little
cada uno pero yo estoy intento lo menos
as possible
todo así como posible
with him in the squid game two
con él en el juego del calamar dos
jokes now We are in Franco's thing
bromas ahora Estamos en lo de Franco
this is also something personal a few times and
este también algo personal pocas veces y
that I think that also as it
que yo creo que además también como nos
happens to us I think to almost all the youtubers
pasa creo que a casi todos los youtubers
that at the beginning we kind of enter very
que al principio como que entramos muy
strong Because we don't have let's say that
fuerte Porque no tenemos digamos esa
constancy of what we can
constancia de lo que podemos llegar a
reach  and we're polishing, he
repercutir y vamos puliendo
hooked up with Fran And I, who was already there, got
enganchó con Fran Y yo que ya estaba a
hooked on riding them at that
mi vez enganché a montarlas en aquella
time. I got hooked up with Fran who
época yo me enganche con Fran qué
thought the same as Dalas and in the end, of
opinaba lo mismo que Dalas y al final
course, he's a man who comes from outside,
claro es un hombre que viene de fuera
comes from another world. Maybe he doesn't understand this whole thing
viene de otro mundo no entienda a lo
about having a
mejor el tema este de que te hagan un
video made criticizing a video that my
vídeo criticando un vídeo que mi
goal was humorous, more than such, you're
objetivo era humorístico más que tal lo
going to want it more like a fool talking eh, I
vas a querer más burro hablando eh yo
watch videos from 3 years ago and without going any
veo vídeos de hace 3 años y sin ir más
further or three years ago and I see myself more like a fool
lejos o tres años y me veo más burro
talking what the [ __ ] man Now I want to
hablando qué la [__] tío Ahora quiero
go to a speech therapist and everything, man Because to
ir a un logopeda y todo tío Porque para
pronounce better It
pronunciar mejor
sounds nice on you, man
Te queda bonito tío
[Music]
[Música]
You can learn to speak better so that your
puedes aprender a hablar mejor para que
vocal cords wear out less, it's
las cuerdas vocales las desgaste menos
true that I notice it's much better
que verdad que se me nota mucho mejor
Speaking now than I did 5 years ago.
Hablando ahora que hace 5 años más
I work all day
Yo trabajo todo el día
with the kid. If I want to have a
con el niño si me los quiero a tomar un
coffee with my father, but I get up, I
café con mi padre pero yo me levanto me
sit here a couple of news stories,
pongo aquí a par de noticias
but all the time I
pero todo el tiempo
hurt so that you vocalize better, so
daño para que vocalices mejor para que
that's not it, and I'm thinking, let's
esa es no es y tengo pensamiento de a
see if I can make some time and go
ver si me hago un hueco y voy la semana
last week I had  that I stop for a day and a half
pasada tuve que parar un día y medio
because I can't speak anymore then so they
porque ya no me sale la voz luego para
see that this is not work You know
que vean que esto no son trabajo Sabes
tell them
díselo
4000 the last Well more or less
4000 el último Pues más o menos
workers
trabajadores
Benidorm which is one of the best
benidorm que es una de las mejores
cities in Spain
ciudades de España
is an apartment and taking into account that you
es un piso y teniendo en cuenta que
get paid in dollars and not the local currency
cobras en dólares y no la moneda local
eh perfectly you can buy all of Latam
eh perfectamente te compras toda latam
without exaggerating or it is not overvalued
sin exageral o no está sobrevalorado de
really 10% is very good but in
verdad el 10% está muy bien pero que en
Peru there are no taxes self-employed there is
Perú tampoco hay impuestos autónomo hay
an income tax which is 15%.  there is another way out
un irpf que es un 15%. hay otra salida
is what chocolate said
es lo que dijo el chocolate
How are you going to be paying the [ __ ] half
Cómo vas a estar pagando la [__] mitad
but not half of course you pay 70
pero no la mitad claro pagas un 70
because you keep half of your
porque tú te quedas con la mitad de tu
money you pay yourself from Spain do
dinero tú te pagas desde España
you know How much money I pay for YouTube in
sabéis Cuánto dinero pago de YouTube en
taxes I pay 70%
impuestos pago un 70%
70%
un 70%
and 20% is for the Treasury crazy
y el 20% es para Hacienda locura
freelancers
autónomos
internet recharges So not the such and
recargas internet Entonces no la de tal
such and this here stop
cual tal cual y esto de aquí pararnos a
the media come on Nothing to do come on I
los medios de comunicación vamos Nada
think everything happens a
que ver vamos yo creo que todo Pasa un
little and look I don't like to get involved in
poco y fíjate que no me gusta meterme en
politics in a public way because more
política ya de manera pública porque más
things are bad than good I think it will happen in
cosas que malas que buenas yo creo que
2023 with this government thrown out which
pasa por el 2023 echadas este gobierno
personally I think are the
que personalmente creo que son los de
dog governments that
los perros gobiernos que han tenido
Spain has had for a long time
España desde hace muchísimo tiempo
starting with Coby ending with the
empezando a por el Coby acabando por los
self-employed and practically with everything that it
autónomos y prácticamente con todo lo
touches which is something that I am very
que toca que es algo que estoy muy
burned out and I who knows but
quemado y a mí que sabe cualquiera pero
please that is the only thing I ask of course and
por favor es lo único que pido claro y
the PP comes out it is the same but disguised in
sale el PP es lo mismo pero disfrazado
blue instead of red
azul en vez de rojo
[Music]
[Música]
40 of the things that  proposes Vox but of
40 de las cosas que propone vox pero de
all the card that is put on the table to me
toda la carta que me pone sobre la mesa
Well, maybe for me the continuation of
Pues a lo mejor a mí que siga la
bullfighting is what will affect me the least
tauromaquia es lo que menos me va a
if weight comes out of bullfighting it
afectar si sale peso de la tauromaquia
will continue no that is not going to eliminate it and
va a seguir no eso no lo va a quitar y
if it gets worse it is not going to eliminate all the
si sale peor tampoco va a quitar a todos
Bankia either. So in the end these are things
los bankia O sea que al final son cosas
that you say Oh it's that you are fascist and you
que tú dices Oh es que tú eres facha y
want to vote for Vox because you want to
quieres votar a vox porque vos quiere
repeal the gender law Well for me as long as they
quitar la ley del género Bueno a mí con
remove the Ministry of Equality or
que quite el Ministerio de igualdad o
whatever it is it works for me and all
sea que sea me sirve y todos los
these Easter scams and things
chiringuitos de estos de pascua y cosas
like that we
así
improve education
mejoramos la educación
there are things that I share eh The regulation
hay cosas que comparto eh La regulación
of rent for example is something that at the
del alquiler por ejemplo es algo que en
time I see the same and that I defend it I
su día lo veo igual y que lo defiendo
think that there are rents that are
que creo que hay alquileres que están
inflated no well In total we
están inflados no bueno Total que nos
have deviated from the subject that you [ __ ] yourself
hemos desviado el tema que te cagas
that you are going to be in the face damn man these
que te vas a la cara ostia tío esta
people are hired by brands not their work
gente los contratan marcas no su trabajo
television
la televisión
is a threat of an aggression okay
es una amenaza de una agresión vale
literally that is how it is it is a threat
literalmente que es así es una amenaza
of aggression I mean this is very strong
de agresión O sea que es muy fuerte esto
any other sector will put a
cualquier otro sector le le ponen un en
play on it  salary of these that they suspend him
play sueldo de estos de que le suspenden
in play salary but here nothing is going to happen
en play sueldo pero aquí no va a pasar
I haven't seen that since the vaquilla and the
Eso no lo veo yo desde el vaquilla y el
torete not someone like that
torete no alguien así
in private because he spoke to me a
por privado porque él me habló hace
long time ago
mucho tiempo
to the two videos that he says So I
a los dos vídeos que dice Entonces yo le
wrote him privately and I said man she
escribí por privado y le he dicho tío ha
was beautiful the answer this the
estado guapa la contestación esto lo
other pim Pam I say let's stay like
otro pim Pam digo quedamos así
this go down to Benidorm let me know if I go up to Madrid I'll let you know and he's there like the bad guy in the movie I don't know what I really have to reflect on I suppose the ways But it's something that is true in a famous person that you like
en una famosa que te gusta
I took out my ID I told him look man I'm
yo saqué mi dni le dije mira tío yo soy
from 97 I just turned 25 this happens this happens this happens that
del 97 tengo 25 años recién cumplidos
then you
pasa esto pasa esto pasa esto que luego
say that bad the truth and really
dices que mal la verdad y realmente
they are lying shamelessly you know You know he was
están mintiendo descaradamente sabes
not 30 years old if he tells me
Sabes que no tenía 30 palos si me dice
that the base unconsciously And he
que la base de manera inconsciente Y
says Well I'll give you a pass he did it
dice Bueno te doy un pase lo hizo
consciously
conciencia
and let's say that other Freestyle that
y digamos que otros Freestyle que
also have me one hundred inclined or
también pues me tienen ciento inclina o
that they don't want me to talk about them or
que no quieren que hable yo de ellos o
criticize him well they told him like a
que le critique pues le dijeron como una
survey  let's say
encuesta digamos
I don't
yo no monetizo
really monetize all this implodes first
realmente todo esto implosiona primero
he says the excuse is that I stole
él dice que la excusa Es que yo le robé
an exclusive from him that was a bit of a no-brainer
una exclusiva que fue un poco sin más
simply on Facebook it was at that
simplemente en Facebook era aquel
moment he was live and he told an
momento estaba en directo y contó una
interesting thing it had already been announced and
cosa interesante ya se había anunciado y
since Facebook literally
como el Facebook no le veía literalmente
nobody saw it I took his, I made an excerpt and put
nadie cogí a su hice un extracto y puse
Rodrigo Quesada announces the exclusive of
Rodrigo Quesada anuncia la exclusiva de
such and truly it was a mystery
tal Y verdaderamente era misterio
telling And from there Well he made
contando Y a partir de ahí Bueno me hizo
a chicken of me that I don't know what And you
un pollo de que no sé qué Y tú te haces
call yourself a journalist and I saw this as a
Llamar periodista y esto lo vi una
true excuse to follow a
excusa verdaderamente para seguir una
trend that is followed in
corriente que la que se sigue en
battles of labeling me and pointing me out as
batallas de etiquetarme y señalarme con
the bad guy because at the
el malo de la película porque él al
beginning he had a very good
principio conmigo tenía muy buena
relationship with me truly he was one of the
relación verdaderamente fue una de las
people inside the glass who the most glasses
personas dentro del cristal que más copa
half that granted me the most interviews that you
medio que más entrevista me concedió que
ask me we did together so I think he
me pides hacíamos juntos entonces creo
wanted to kind of distance himself from me
que quiso como alejarse mucho de mí
because let's say that his friends and his
porque digamos que sus amistades y su
circle hate me they don't have a certain
círculo me odia no me tienen cierta en
quint or they don't directly want me to
quina o no quieren directamente que
belong to the guild
pertenezca al gremio
automatically every time you are on
automáticamente cada vez que estás en
YouTube on YouTube no no
YouTube en YouTube no no
[Music]
[Música]
of the battle
de las batalla
the panorama because I offer the  criticism
el panorama porque ofrezco la crítica
that nobody offers and you are the
que nadie ofrece y ustedes son los
protagonists of this So let's see
protagonistas de esto Entonces vamos
how they bring the positions
como acercan posturas
of the Analysis closer together, it's all the battle,
del Análisis es de todo la batalla
the copyright from audio and image of
el copyright desde audio y de imagen
course, the secondary channel, well in the end it does
claro el canal secundario pues al final
n't use as much battle content, I mean, it does
no usa tanto contenido de batallas O sea
n't use as many images plus me talking
no usa tanta imágenes más yo hablando
like it could be a video of yours
como puede ser un vídeo tuyo
with the whole ending, I mean, it's with the
con todo el final o sea es con la
company Urban Rooster but it's that
empresa Urban rooster pero es que ella
in itself Red Bull and Gol Level which are
de por sí Red Bull y gol Level que son
other very important competitions
otras competencias muy importantes
It's as if I made a campaign so
Es como si yo hiciera una campaña para
that they would never call x freestyler to an
que no llamarán x freestyler jamás a un
event and that's something I would never do I
evento y eso es algo que jamás haría
hope they call them as many times as
Ojalá les llamen todas las veces
possible and get rich
posibles y se hagan ricos
but the other day I was saying that or
pero el otro día estaba diciendo que o
the other one said that you didn't have the ESO, I don't have
lo dijo el otro que no tenías la eso no
journalism in the end, journalism
periodismo al final el periodismo
requires previously studying
le hace falta estudiar previamente la
carpentry to practice, I had
carpintería para ejercer yo me salían
16 years of ESO and I started
los 16 años de la eso y empecé a
working in the media on
trabajar en medio de comunicación en
television and
televisión
now I have nothing to do with him with
ya ya no tengo nada que ver con él con
that channel also Javier Ortegas,
ese canal también a Javier ortegas
effectively in Benidorm,
efectivamente en benidorm
before I
antes
used it to save all my
lo usaba para guardar todos mis archivos
journalistic files and if you go to my channel and
periodísticos y si vas a mi canal y
put the oldest ones
pones los más antiguos
from radio  television, that's why the
de radio de televisión
journalist thing
por eso lo de periodista
[Music]
[Música]
anyway, with that, that's
de todas formas tú con la Eso sí es
enough for them to call you for
suficiente como para que te llamen para
any television program
cualquier programa de televisión
[Music]
[Música]
or of course tomorrow
o por supuesto el día de mañana ya
when they call you to be a collaborator on
cuando te llamen para ser colaborador de
any Big Brother-type program, you'll
cualquier programa de corte gran hermano
eat them up, what do they get if he
en plan total te los comes qué cogen si
's more trained than all of them, but
está más entrenado que todos ellos pero
not for nothing because Fran is already calling me.
no por nada porque me está llamando ya
Thanks, dude, for inviting me, it's
Fran Gracias chulo por invitarme está
very good
muy bien
[Music]
[Música]